Guide to the Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering records, 1917-2009.
Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering records, 1917-2009.
16-5-1151
Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering.
14.5 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, photographs, printed material, research material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, course material, and equipment manuals of the Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, formerly the Sibley School of Mechanical Engineering. Also the papers of Charles Osborn Mackey, Howard N. Fairchild, and Frank Oakes Ellenwood.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, course material, and equipment manuals of the Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, formerly the Sibley School of Mechanical Engineering. Also the papers of Charles Osborn Mackey, Howard N. Fairchild, and Frank Oakes Ellenwood.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering.; Ellenwood, Frank O.(Frank Oakes), 1878-; Fairchild, Howard N.; Mackey, Charles O.(Charles Osborn), 1903-; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Sibley School of Mechanical Engineering.
Subjects:
Mechanical engineering--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Lantern slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Includes collection #16-5-508, and #16-5-993.
CONTAINER LIST
- Course Material, Correspondence, and Technical Documents
  - B-W Hot room tests 1955, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Room cooling unit- 1956 specifications of room window air-conditioners, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Controls- designs of systems, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Data sheets for runs of compressor Aug. 1955 Carrier Warthermaker model 38b data, Meeting notes about air-conditioners July 1955 to C.O. Mackey, Sketches and equations, Aug. 55 Data about freon flow, 1955-08 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Articles about Air-conditioning, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Truck Refrigeration report to Johnson from Mackey, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Refrigeration test rack project- Blue prints and data 12/55, 1955-12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Information on vehicle cooling, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hermetic Compressors- data, graphs and articles, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Refrigeration tests and standards, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Refrigeration test rack Passenger car cooling 1956- graphs, charts, articles, blueprint, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bendix-Westinghouse research 1957 reports and graphs about cooling project, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - B-W Lecture notes up to lecture #8, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - B-W Spare notes (lots of charts), Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Passenger car cooling project- 1954-5 (info from car companies), 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Memos from Bendix 57-58, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bendix research proposals, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Transportation Unlimited presentation Jan. 1955, 1955-01 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stall summer research 1957, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - B-W Hermetic summer 1956- memos and reports, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - B-W office flow 1955- charts, graphs and other information, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Articles About Heat Exchangers, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Articles About Moisture and Drying, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Survey of the air conditioner compressor market Oct. 1955, 1955-10 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Articles About Residential Air Conditioning, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
  - 1920's Literature on, and other literature on refrigeration, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cottrell Precipitator- A.F. Mestou 5/43 "Removal of suspended particles from furnace gases and other gases", 1943-05 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1930-1949 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Research for Bulletin #30, Oct. '42- Specific Heats of Certain Gases, 1942-10 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondences about Bulletin #30, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Notes 3p41 and 3p42 F.O. Ellenwood- chart, data and equations, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - F.O. Ellenwood Book- chapters 38, 39, 42, 43, 44, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letters and Reports to F.O. Ellenwood 1930s, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 35-37)
  - Bulletins 9 (mar '28) 34 (Dec '44), Sept. 24 publication by F.O. Ellenwood "Maximum possible boiler efficiencies", 1928, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Reports: Gas and Electric bills from 1933, Boilers etc. 1942, Cost of large compressors 1924, 1924, 1933, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 1955-56 correspondences and reports- Kimball + Mackey, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Diagrams, reports, some correspondence Mackey and Fitch 1957-58, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Truck Refrigeration Design Charts 1957, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Air Conditioning program (includes brochures and some meeting minutes) 1953-54, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Automotive refrigeration tests Frank Haag 1956-57, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reports on trips June 1957 from E.B. Watson, 1957-06 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - York Air conditioning system 1957- graphs, memos, designs, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bendix answers to questionnaires 1957, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hermatic Compressor Heat Transfer, Freon-22 1957- Brochures, reports, graphs, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Truek refrigeration- graphs 1957, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sunstrand Hydraulic drive- Brochures and memos 1957, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - B-W Automotive RD-l00 1955 Charts and graphs, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - B-W R-D 102 Automotive compressor 1955 charts graphs and designs, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Compressor capacity control 1957 brochures, sketches and equations, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - B-W Automotive RD-101 1955 charts, graphs and memos, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Car air-conditioning articles 1955, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Articles and correspondences re: air-conditioning 1955 Mackey and Morris, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - First interim report Bendix-Westinghouse research 8/57 Refrigerating systems for straight truck bodies, 1957-08 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Second interim report Bendix-Westinghouse research 9/57 Refrigerating systems for straight truck bodies, 1957-09 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Refrigeration research project- change of objective (no dates), Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Truck refrigeration design charts 1957, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sproul- Packless Metal Baseboard 1940- Equasions, charts, info., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - SF Iszard Elmira NY 1949 charts, equations, memos, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Clinton Hotel renovations 1949, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - College Spa, 1947 Blank forms, Charts, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Radio rooms savings bank building- measurements (no dates), Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1949-41 Correspondences and Brochures from cooling companies, 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Rogers Fuel Pump flow problem 1946, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Progress repon H.H. Stevens Heat Study 12/41, 1941-12 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - New Haven Tests- mostly 1942 Reports, articles, designs etc., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Radiant Heating- John B. Pierce 1943 report, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Frame Test Room 1943 Information and blueprints etc., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
  - Heat Information- C. Mackey early 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - Sol Air Temperature - Sol Air Thermometer, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Development of a Sol-Air Thermometer - 5th year project - William, Messina, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 3P58 Prelims and Final, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 3P55 Finals-1937-42; 3P57 Prelims 1936-37; and Exams-1939-40, 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 3P48 Prelims, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 3P57 Prelims and Final-1940-41; 3P57 and 3P58 Prelims and Final-1938-39, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Prelims and Finals, 1937-1943 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Refrigeration - 3P49 - FD Hart, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Fluid Mechanics, Date Unknown (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Advanced Thermodynamics, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Thermodynamics - Steam Turbines, 1938, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Combustion- Flame Characteristics as Affecting Engine Economy and Reliability- C.A. French, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "The Rationale of Air Distribution and Grille Performance" - C.O. Mackey, includes correspondence, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence between Mr. Carrier and Mr. Viljoen; Mr. Carrier and Prof. Mackey and notes, 1940-1949 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Cold Storage Locker Plants - Quick Freezing, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Proposed GLF Locker Storage Plant - Prof Mackey, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Report to G.L.F.lnc., Ithaca, NY - by York Ice Machinery Co., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Water Rates in Ithaca, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Letter to Prof. Mackey from Lennox Furnace Co, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Finned Surface Heat Transfer Co. - Mackey, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Tests - Mackey, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - A.S.H.V.E. - contract and costs - Hollister, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - TAC cooling load, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
  - Proposal for engineering study relating to noise reduction of ground equipment, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ASRE Data Book, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ASRE Data Book Revisions, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mercury Aircraft, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - EJAY MFG Co. Baseboard tests, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - American - La France Bills, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Psychometry, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Psychometry - "Thermodynamic Properties of Moist Air", Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Westinghouse Research Fund- plans, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Engineering reports, 1937, 1944-1947 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Spar-Holl Tests, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Regenerator for gas turbine - Young Radiator Co., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Looey Super- Topping Turbine, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Research- mostly correspondence about test facilities - Mackey, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Instruction book cyclotherm steam generator, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Combustion research, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Engine Test Facilities, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sahab Floor, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Consolidated Edison Heat Pump, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - CMA Housing Research, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - American Society of Refrigerating Engineers (ASRE) Research Proposal, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "Appraisal of the Gas Turbine as Carriage Power Supply", 1951 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Utica Radiator Reports, 1948-1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Tuttle and Bailey - Report on Kulene 131, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Extended Surface Heat Transfer Equipment, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Glass Blocks, Heat gains, - report prepared for Owens Dlinois - Mackey, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Heating problem - Rosefsky, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Kimble Glass, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Kimble- heat gain through skylights, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
  - Commercial pump tests - American - La France, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Kold-Hold Mfg. Co. - baseboard tests, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Gilmore and Wheeler Proposal re: Waterbury Furnace for Rosefsky, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Home of Le Davis, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Biggerstaff Residence - heating specifiacations, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Diaphragm compressor effects of altitude and clearance on capacity and volumetric efficiency -Mackey, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Raditors - correspondence with Byrley, 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Lee-Vine Finned Tube Radiation, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - American La France - Multi-Fog Pump, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Test codes convectors baseboard, 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Beacon-Morris Convector Tests, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Anemostat Co., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Iszard Humidifier, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Fedders-Quigan, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Test room info-Photo Elastic Lab and East Mech Lab, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Round-Robin Baseboard Testing, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - CMA Calculations - effective heat and loss calculations report and equasions-Mackey, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - LAPP Insulator Co., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Con Edison - Cooling Load, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - CMA Papers - Ashve, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Frankfort Arsenal, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - American - La France - Reports, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Utica Tests- Fins - Mackey, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Utica Radiator Co., 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 60-62)
  - VFW Owego-air conditioning loads, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Cornell- Air conditioning, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Ithaca Gun Co., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Mackesey residence- heating specifications, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - CMA Research Residence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - C02 Heating System American-La France, 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Sears Baseboard, 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Dr. Francis Ward- air conditioning, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Photographs CMA tests, Date Unknown (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Babcock and Wilcox, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Annual report of the Vice President for Research at Cornell, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Development and Application of Contact Mixture Principle to Convection Heat Transfer and Pressure Drop of Air Flowing Across In- Line Tube Banks- Mackey, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Heat Transfer, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Transfer Research and Proposal, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Various Heat Transfer Materials and Babacock and Wilcox Data sheets, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Reports - Mackey, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Vibration and its Effect on Heat Transfer" - by Mason and Bolelter, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cross Flow Heat Transfer Research, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Report on Babcock and Wilcox Project - D. Dropkin, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Data Orifice Calabration, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Bulletin-Series 1 & 2, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Babcock and Wilcox summer work, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Babcock and Wilcox summer work, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Heat Transfer, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Contact Factor, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Heat Transfer Computations, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Uncertainty Interval, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correlation of test data - Heat Transfer, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Heat Transfer Proposals - Babcock and Wilcox, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Unlabelled Data Sheets, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - Non-Tangent Tube Data Series 1 and 2, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Data Sheets, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Unlabeled graphs and equations, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
  - Heat transfer - Fairchild and Welch, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Babcock and Wilcox- row by row data, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Babcock and Wilcox curves, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Heat transfer and pressure drop data tabulation, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
  - Cross Flow Heat Transfer, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 35-37)
  - Babcock and Wilcox work- Yang, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Yang-report of curves, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Babcock and Wilcox computations, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Heat Transfer Data, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Heat Transfer Report, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Research Project - Report 22, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 5-7)
  - Heat Transfer Info - Mackey, 1958-1961 (Box 5, Folder 8-11)
  - Transactions of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Babcock and Wilcox (B & W) Research Project - SE Monroe, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - B& W Tangent Tube Data - row by row, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - B&W Tangent Tube Data - 10 row - final form, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - B&W Research Project Reports, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - B&W correspondence, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Unlabeled data, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Pressure drop from acceleration, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - AC Moore Correlation of Troy, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - B& W correspondence, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - B&W series 3 data, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Unlabeled graphs and sketches, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
  - Contact mixture principle heat transfer - Mackey, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Tangent series, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - B&W original drawings, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - B&W Curves of results, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Transactions of the ASME, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - B& W material for Bulletin, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Heat Transfer material, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Interim Reports Heat transfer and Pressure Drop, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - B& W material for Bulletin - results, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Heat Transfer Report, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - B&W individual row heat transfer, Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - B&W "Individual Row Heat Transfer in a Cross-Flow In-line Tube Bank", Date Unknown (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Fairchild and Welch, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - B&W, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - B&W, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Unlabelled Graphs and Equations, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - B&W Extended Surface, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - B&W Summer, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Boiler Info, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Transactions of the ASME, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Interim Report - tests, 1958-06 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Heat Transfer, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Log of Test Data Runs 50+, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - B&W Report 59 -10, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - B&W Row-by Row Analysis, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - B&W Sample Sheets, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Pierson Pressure Drop Data, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - B&W Research Project - Supplementary Log of Test and Computations, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - B&W Crossflow Heat Transfer - 1st Draft of Proposed Papers for ASME, 1956-06 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Heat Transfer Info., Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Bulletin Material Series 1&2, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Row-By-Row, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - IBM Brochures, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Fall Term Conta, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Brochures, Inventories- Mackey, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Course 3508 Heat Power, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Prelims - Automatic Control Engineers 3670, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Elective Course - Rockets (Skinner), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - New Courses, 1948-1950 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Combustion, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Conductivity, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Constant Temperature, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Dew Point, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Dynamometers, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Electric, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Electric, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Fan Tests, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Flow, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Flow, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Gas Analysis, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Heating Units, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Humidity, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Indicators, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Liquid Level, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Manometers, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Mechanical Regulators, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Photographic, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Low-Temp Cabinet, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Pressure, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Scales, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Sound, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Speed, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Temperature, 1943-1952 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Temperature, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Calculations and Graphs (Oversize), Date Unknown (Box 6)
  - Air Conditioning Apparatus - talk by C.O. Mackey (1946), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Air Conditioning Lab- Instructor - C.O. Mackey - Student Miller S.S. - grade received 85 - date - 2/8/1946, 1946-02-08 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Air Conditioning Lab - Instructor - Mackey - Student - Richard Jordan - grade received 70 - date - 1946, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Air Conditioning Lab by Richard Jordan -Course ME 13 grade 80, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Air Conditioning Lab Reports - 1946, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Air Conditioning Labs, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Allison Engines - On loan from Anny Air Forces - 1944, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Locomotive Co. - Equipment diagrams, plans, photos: Macintosh and Seymour Engine, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Babcock + Wilcox Boiler Conversion - 1943, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Buffalo Forge Co. - Drawings, Operating Instructions: Oil Burners, Atomizers, Type CB Blower - 1950, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Carrier Condensing Unit - Instructions for Calorimeter, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Course - Flue Gas Analysis + Boiler Water Conditioning - 1944, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Course Labs + Outlines - 1944, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Course Outlines - Naval Training School, Hydraulic Flow, Steam Calorimetry, Pressure + Temperature Measurements, etc., Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Course - Report Outlines, Labs - 1943 - 44, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Data York 10/28-31, 1946, 1946-10-28-1946-10-31 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Demonstration Board - Operating Instructions, Wiring and Piping Blueprints, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Description + Instructions Covering the Westinghouse Operational Demonstration Board for Domestic Refrigerator Units, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "The Design of a 30" Closed- Throat Non-Return Wind Tunnel Fw the Dept. of Mechanical Engineering Lab, Cornell University - by Lynn Bussey - 1946, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Elementary Navy V-S 143G Session - 1943 - 48, 1943-1948 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Final Exam - Mechanical Engineering - 1947, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Food Engineering - Course 3510, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Frick Compound Compression System, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - General Electric - Suggested Experiments Using the Educational Unit Power Plant, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - General Electric Refrigerator + Motor Generator Set Switchboard, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Hot - Wire Anemometer, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Instruction Book - Westinghouse Steam Lab Equipment - 1947, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Labs - Course 3502, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Lab - Flue G'dS Analysis + Boiler Water Conditioning - done by J.R Anderson - 1943 - Instructor Mackey, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Manuals, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Mechanical Engineering Prelim Questions + Final - 1945, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Plans, Blueprints, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Refrigeration Lab -John Holmes - grade 85 - Carrier 7K4 - 50WF Unit - Lab by Briel- grade 75 - 1945, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Repair of York Compressor, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Reprints (1940; 41), Requisitions, Correspondence (1949), Mechanical Engineering Research Project (late 1930's), 1935-1949 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Test Results of Carrier Unit - 1946, 1947, 1935-1939, 1940-1941, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Steam Laboratory Equipment for Cornell- 1948, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Stress Analysis of the Propeller Blade for the 57" Wind Tunner Fan - Henry EgI, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 38)